Harpreet Kaur

Brampton ON, L7A 4R7 | 437-998-2106 | hkaur 108@hotmail.com

Check out: https://hkaur108.github.io/portfolio/

WEB DEVELOPER

Self-motivated IT Developer with education in computer science and experience in technical support. Analytical problem solver with a keen curiosity, a passion for learning and a strong attention to detail. Open communicator and collaborator works well in a fast-paced diverse team environment.

KEY SKILLS

Front-End Engineering | Responsive Web Design | SVG | Technology Support | Customer Service | Analytical Problem Solving | Troubleshooting | Creative Design | Cross-Functional Collaboration | Stakeholder Management.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Language: CSS, React, JQuery, Git, Javascript, HTML, Responsive Web Design, SVG.
- Database: MySQL, MongooseDb.
- Networking: TCP/IP, FTP, VPN, Ethereal & Wireshark
- Operating System: Windows, Linux, Active Directory, Windows Server 2016.
- Backend Technologies: Nodejs, Mongoose, EJS. Web Sockets, Restful APIs, NPM, MVC, HTTP Methods.

EDUCATION

Cyber Security and Computer Forensics Post Graduate Diploma

Lambton College

Bachelor of Computer Applications, B.C.A.

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University, Delhi, India

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- Web Development Bootcamp | Udemy
- Creating Responsive Web Design | LinkedIn
- Learning SVG | LinkedIn
- Comptia A+ Certification | Comptia
- AlarmForce Certified Technician | Sponsored by AlarmForce

WORK EXPERIENCE

Alarmforce Industries Inc., Toronto, ON

March 2022 - May 2024

Technical Support Associate

Answered inbound calls pertaining to technical issues related to the alarm system; troubleshoot issues with video devices and security systems and booked technicians if required.

- Used Live video assistance to remotely assist customers which resulted in increment in customer satisfaction by 8%.
- Contributed to the training material to improve the team's overall growth and learning, which resulted in a 10% increase in team's productivity.

- Provided reset password links to customers not able to login to the app or the online portal.
- Follow up with the customer to check whether they are satisfied by the technician's job on site and then
 document accounts with the information provided by the customer if required another appointment is
 booked.

Skanna Security and Investigations, Scarborough, ON Loss Prevention Supervisor

June 2018 - February 2022

Worked as a Loss prevention officer handling front desk responsibilities and monitoring video surveillance.

- Trained team members and guided them for routine tasks and trained them on CCTV usage and emphasized on following the company's SOP, which increased team efficiency by 5%.
- Monitoring other officers and providing them with timely performance feedback which resulted in performance improvement and employee satisfaction.

Convergys India Ltd, Gurugram Haryana

April 2014 - August 2017

Technical Support Associate

Answered inbound calls related to handset and network problems; opened and escalated to 2nd level support team if required.

- Followed the call flow guide to properly answer calls and resolve issues.
- Connected calls to the correct department in case the client wants to purchase any additional products and services.
- Maintained the proper documentation of the call and retrieved data accordingly.